One man's extraordinary fight to save the family he loved.
Cinderella Man is a romance, drama, history film directed by Ron Howard.
The true story of boxer Jim Braddock who, following his retirement in the 1930s,
makes a surprise comeback in order to lift his family out of poverty.
Jim Braddock, played by Russell Crowe.
Mae Braddock, played by Renée Zellweger.
Joe Gould, played by Paul Giamatti.
Max Baer, played by Craig Bierko.
Mike Wilson, played by Paddy Considine.
Jimmy Johnston, played by Bruce McGill.
Cinderella Man is a 2005 American biographical
drama film directed by Ron Howard.
The film stars Russell Crowe, Renée Zellweger, and Paul Giamatti.
It tells the true story of heavyweight boxing champion James J.
Braddock, who was dubbed "The Cinderella Man" by journalist Damon Runyon.
The film marked the second collaboration for Howard and
Crowe, succeeding A Beautiful Mind (2001).
Universal Pictures and Miramax Films released Cinderella
Man in the United States on June 3, 2005.
It received generally positive reviews from critics
and grossed $108 million worldwide.
Cinderella Man received three Academy Award nominations,
including Best Supporting Actor for Giamatti.
Crowe and Giamatti both received Golden Globe Award and Screen Actors Guild Award nominations for their
performances, and Giamatti won the latter alongside a Critics' Choice Movie Award for Best Supporting Actor.
Retrospective critical reviews have named Cinderella Man as
one of the greatest boxing films of all time.
The film explores themes of daughter, transporter,
sports, world cup, irish-american.
The tone is emotional.